<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CSU Online Learning Exchange</title>
    <description>Developed and Maintained by Charles Sturt University&#39;s u!magine</description>
    <link>/csulx/</link>
    <atom:link href="/csulx/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 17:22:51 +1000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 17:22:51 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Video Lectures</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video Lectures&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;element-tags&quot;&gt;Element Tags&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teacher Presence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recording Video Lectures for online students provides a richer engagement with the subject concepts than is possible with text. The sound and ‘live’ nature of the resource helps to convey the presence of the teacher. The tone of voice and other aspects of the audio contribute to students understanding of the topic and possible nuances in concepts. Video provides a rich medium to convey information as it can combine visual elements with animation and footage of the lecturer speaking. It also provides an avenue to embed and share some of the teacher’s personality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;engagement&quot;&gt;Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video Lectures provide a version of ‘the lecture’ that is more tailored to the online environment. CSU Replay recordings of the internal lecture can sometimes have issues with the audio as the lecturer moves in relation to the microphone and can come across to students as second best. Specifically recording videos shifts the priority to the online students and opens up new possibilities for internal students as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-practice&quot;&gt;In Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;subject&quot;&gt;Subject&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SCI103&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;teaching-staff&quot;&gt;Teaching staff&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ana Horta&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Video Lectures help the online students to feel that they are not missing out because of their study mode. They provide an effective way of augmenting the existing content students have and provide a timely way to address questions and provide support to the whole cohort of students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;implementation&quot;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SCI103 video lectures include screen-captures as well as audio and video, and mostly range from 20-40 minutes. They were created to provide online students with more coverage and explanation of the concepts presented in the online modules, textbook and recommended readings. Like lectures, there is one for each week. Through these video lectures the voice and personality of the lecturer comes through as a real human being, and so helps convey teacher presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guide&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video lectures can be utilised in a variety of ways to augment and support your teaching and engagement with students. They provide a way to communicate directly with the class as a whole but also provide a channel to embed your personality into the subject too. There are however some pitfalls in that make transferring lectures done face-to-face quite challenging, but also some important affordance you can take advantage of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maintaining Attention&lt;/strong&gt; - This can be a challenge in a video and it’s why many experts suggest keeping the length of online videos short. There are often more distractions available when studying online and it’s a lot easier to duck off to another Tab in the browser than it is to leave a classroom.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audio and Visuals&lt;/strong&gt; - Videos require an effort to both audio and visual components. Talking to a single slide is quite common in a face-to-face lecture because there is other visual stimuli available, but that’s not the case in a video. Spending less time on a slide and creating some visual diversity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pause and Rewind&lt;/strong&gt; - One of the unique aspects of video lectures is that it provides students with the ability to pause and rewind. Pausing means that they can come back to the lecture and provides students with added flexibility. The rewind allows students to re-watch the video multiple times. This is great for demonstrations or showing processes to student. It allows them to see how it fits together.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communicate&lt;/strong&gt; - Use video lectures to maintain a dialogue with your students. Keep them up to date with their progress, upcoming deadlines, tips for study and assessment tasks and respond to their questions from the forums or email as a group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.csu.edu.au/division/dit/staff/training/self-help/teaching-technology-and-support&quot;&gt;CSU Replay&lt;/a&gt; provides a desktop capture solution that allows you to record and upload presentations back into the system for students to access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;apa-ref&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Anderson, T., Rourke, L., Garrison, D. R., &amp;amp; Archer, W. (2001). Assessing teacher presence in a computer conferencing context. &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://auspace.athabascau.ca/bitstream/2149/2725/2141/assessing_teaching_presence.pdf%20on%20Oct-2014&quot;&gt;Journal of the Asynchronous Learning Network, 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;(2),&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Anderson T. (Ed.), (2008) &lt;em&gt;Theory and practice of online learning&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 343-365). Athabasca University, Edmonton, AB: AU Press.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Arbaugh, J. B. (2001). How Instructor Immediacy Behaviors Affect Student Satisfaction and Learning in Web-Based Courses. [Article]. &lt;em&gt;Business Communication Quarterly, 64&lt;/em&gt;(4), 42-54.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Borup, J. West, R.E., Graham C.R. (2012) &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S109675161100073X&quot;&gt;The Internet and Higher Education&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, Elsevier&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Dunlap, J. C., &amp;amp; Lowenthal, P. R. (2009). Tweeting the Night Away: Using Twitter to Enhance Social Presence. [Article]. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Information Systems Education, 20&lt;/em&gt;(2), 129-135.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Garrison, D. R., &amp;amp; Arbaugh, J. B. (2007). Researching the community of inquiry framework: Review, issues, and future directions. &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.iheduc.2007.04.001&quot;&gt;The Internet and Higher Education, 10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;(3), 157-172. and p.168&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Ostashewski, N. (2015). A tale of three MOOCs: Designing for meaningful teacher presence in large-enrolment courses. In S. Carliner, C. Fulford &amp;amp; N. Ostashewski (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of EdMedia: World Conference on Educational Media and Technology 2015&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 2015, pp. 1279-1284): Association for the Advancement of Computing in Education (AACE).&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Sheridan, T. B. (1992). Musings on telepresence and virtual presence. &lt;em&gt;Presence: Teleoper. Virtual Environ.&lt;/em&gt;, 1(1), 120-126 mentions video as part of conveying telepresence&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Swan, K., Shea, P., Richardson, J., Ice, P., Garrison, D., Cleveland-Innes, M., et al. (2008). Validating a measurement tool of presence in online communities of inquiry. &lt;em&gt;E-mentor, 2&lt;/em&gt;(24), 1-12.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 16:20:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>/csulx/strategy/video-lectures.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/csulx/strategy/video-lectures.html</guid>
        
        <category>Teacher Presence</category>
        
        <category>Interactive Resources</category>
        
        
        <category>strategy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating Rich Media Artefacts</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The creation of rich media artefacts including photographic evidence, video records and multimedia presentations by learners can provide an authentic way for learners to develop a variety of digital literacies, technical and communication skills that will be useful in the professions. In addition, the co-construction of rich media artefacts can also offer an authentic collaborative experience for learners and due to advancing and readily available mobile technologies, a range of interactive experiences can be integrated into the collaborative learning environment. In many ways rich media such as video can provide better evidence of students work and their skills and abilities which can greatly improve the effectiveness of the assessment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;engagement&quot;&gt;Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of rich media artefacts can create an engaging learning experience by shifting the attention away from the physical product and on to the learning process. Learners can also engage further self and peer assessment and reflection in an authentic setting. Working with rich media provides an alternative to written assessment tasks and a way for students to express themselves in different ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guide&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rich Media provides a different way for students to document, explain or demonstrate their learning. It provides ways of capturing information about what students are learning that are not possible in other mediums. Rich media can capture important information about the student’s environment and situation and provides a way to capture more authentic tasks - in particular getting students to demonstrate and reflect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some important considerations for structuring assessments that utilise rich media include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build additional work around the task. Developing rich media can be time consuming so don’t use it as an add on, but look at opportunities to centre other assessments or activities the student’s work to make it worthwhile.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use it for self-evaluation and diagnosis. Ask students to record themselves and let them review their performance and get them to link their work to theory and the profession.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build relevant skills with a focus on the what they would benefit from in the profession. What would they do on the job? Tasks that are common and adaptable are presentations of information and literature, in depth discussion of a situation or topic, or taking a side and creating an argument for a debate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rich media lends itself particularly well to engaging in peer-to-peer evaluation and feedback on the work. Students could be asked not just to to identify issues but to make suggestion and provide constructive feedback which is often quite challenging, but engages a deeper level of knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To know if using rich media is the right choice in your subject then ask yourself some of the following questions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can it provide you with better evidence to assess your students?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Will it capture the student’s learning better than an essay?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is it a more authentic and more contextual way to assess the student?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many readily available tools that students can utilise to produce rich media artefacts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mobile devices can record audio and video as well as take photos.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use Powerpoint and similar software to combine audio and visuals.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;YouTube, Vimeo, SoundCloud and Flickr provide free and easy ways for students to publish their artefacts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;apa-ref&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Klapdor, T. (2014). Recording video on your Mobile, &lt;em&gt;CSU mHub&lt;/em&gt;. Retrieved 19 July 2016, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://mhub.csu.edu.au/guides/recording-video-on-your-mobile/&quot;&gt;http://mhub.csu.edu.au/guides/recording-video-on-your-mobile/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 12:34:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>/csulx/strategy/creating-rich-media-artefacts.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/csulx/strategy/creating-rich-media-artefacts.html</guid>
        
        <category>Interactive Resources</category>
        
        <category>E-Assessment</category>
        
        
        <category>strategy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Computer Based Exams</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A computer based exam is a an exam which replaces the more traditional paper based exam and may or may not involve the use of a remote indivigulator to monitor the student/s during the completion of the task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;engagement&quot;&gt;Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The provision of computer based exams provide students with a contemporary and flexible method of completing assessment tasks. This approach is more in keeping with the ways that students complete other assessment tasks (i.e. with computers) and is a more flexible practice than the requirement for students to travel to their nearest exam centre to sit a paper based exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-practice&quot;&gt;In Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;subject&quot;&gt;Subject&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HIP202 Research for Health Practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;teaching-staff&quot;&gt;Teaching staff&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Kylie Murphy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;HIP202 Research For Health Practice&lt;/em&gt; is a second year common subject undertaken by most students within the school of Community Health at CSU. The aim of this subject is to begin these students on the journey to becoming evidence based health practitioners. This subject is designed to provide students with an introductory experience to utilising information and research and applying this knowledge to the specific problems of their health discipline/s. Throughout this subject students are taught to, and get the chance to implement a range of skills including the development of sophisticated database search terms (including Boolean operators) creating and saving database permalinks, understanding the structure and function of a wide range of qualitative and qualitative research approaches and associated documentation. Students become skilled at doing all of these things to solve authentic problems over the course of the subject, so the apparent misalignment between the subject and it’s main assessment task, a paper based exam, were clear. Providing students with a large collection of printed resources was both in-authentic and wasteful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;implementation&quot;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating a suitable replacement task for this paper based exam revolved around firstly determining alignment between subject outcomes, the assessable components in question and then ensuring that students could access a fair and well designed assessment which was supported by current CSU platforms. In the end, the Interact2 test centre was chosen as the platform because of the support available and (through an extended period of testing and trialing) the ability to remove technical glitches. Over 190 students completed the assessment task simultaneously in a three hour period during exam week in July 2016, with all three student cohorts reporting an increased satisfaction of the subject and the assessment practices, as measured by the student experience survey. Key messages from this implementation process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A team development process is crucial-as the academic, developing and building a vision for what you want to achieve in innovating in your assessments is crucial, but getting people around you so that you can access the right skills at the right time is key-your educational designer can support you with project management on these larger tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sustainability versus ‘do-ability’-at some point, when you have less support, will you be able to carry out some of the trouble shooting yourself? Investing time upfront in understanding how the system will work will gain you time in the long term.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Starting point-critically analyse what you are offering as assessment, not just how you are offering it-consider all parts when undertaking assessment changes-who, what, when, where, how, why…and for who.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be explicit in linking between learning outcomes and design of the e-exam-particularly useful so that students could see why the changes were being made in this research and information literacy subject&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integrate the e-exam into the delivery of the subject i.e. providing advance notice through announcements, practice e-exams, pre-emptive student troubleshooting tips, familiarisation. In essence, consider the user experience of your e-exam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guide&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking to implement a computer based exam within your subject/s, there are some important considerations to make when planning this approach:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integrity - Given that many exams at CSU are relatively high stakes, it is important to take into account the ways which you will maintain the integrity of the assessment task so that students are assessed on a level playing field. If you are planning on utilizing the increasing range of remote invigilator services available (see here) these concerns are somewhat minimized as the student’s identification will be verified by the invigilator.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design - If you are not planning on utilising these kinds invigilator services, the design of the exam can increase the integrity of the assessment. For example, an exam containing extended answer sections to complement multiple choice questions gives you as the assessor greater opportunity to cross reference any work against the student’s prior performance within the subject.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exam platform - It is possible to build an effective e-exam within the interact2 test environment. A growing practice is the creation of one overall exam which consists of several ‘tests’, each of which can only be accessed once the previous one has been reviewed and submitted. This has several advantages including the fact that you can choose to make students complete the exam in a specified or random order, and as a result it minimises chances for integrity breaches. In addition, there are a range of functionalities such as the ability to store audio, video and files within the test environment, these being available from other areas of your subject site. Additionally, utilizing the supported test centre functionalities within interact2 means that you can schedule specific opening and closing times for these assessment tasks, meaning that support can be organised around this timeframe.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Another effective safeguard in ensuring integrity is undertaking a range of pre-moderation activities. In a typical exam environment, students will be presented with the same scenario. In an e-exam, it is possible to present a range of scenarios in which students are asked to apply knowledge and skills. Key to this is the development and pre-moderation of a range of equivalent scenarios that students must respond to. The alternative to this aspect is providing one scenario but a range of ways to respond. Building a range of options makes it harder for collusion to occur, but it is important to follow a rigorous pre- moderation process.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are other non-supported technologies for offering e-exams, but utilising these is problematic as they will not link to CSU systems such as grade centre. In some situations bespoke solutions can be created in order to embed currently unsupported software platforms, but this process requires an extensive planning and implementation time frame.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interact2 - various tools including Test Centre and Grade Centre are important in the design and development of your computer based exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content Creation - you may need to utilise a range of tools including word processing programs such as Word or Pages. Alternatively, Test Centre does have a range of content creation tools including Word/Audio/Video which can be deployed in the test environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 10:37:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>/csulx/strategy/computer-based-exams.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/csulx/strategy/computer-based-exams.html</guid>
        
        <category>Flexible &amp; Adaptive Learning</category>
        
        <category>E-Assessment</category>
        
        
        <category>strategy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Online Marking &amp; Effective Feedback</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is well established that students benefit from constructive feedback on their learning. Everyday learning activities as well as special tasks and tests provide opportunities for the provision of feedback. Online marking presents a diverse range of tools that are designed for provide much richer options for feedback to students that include verbal, visual and written feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;engagement&quot;&gt;Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The digital tools available today can increase the personalisation possible and can greatly increase the turnaround time. The ability and ease in which quality audio feedback can be incorporated into the marking process can have many positive effects. The students engagement in their assessments is improved with personalised feedback and the teacher’s voice can make distance students feel more connected and reduce feelings of isolations. The use of verbal feedback provides a link for students with someone they know, that is not just a name in a subject outline but a real person, who cares about their progress and achievements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-practice&quot;&gt;In Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;subject&quot;&gt;Subject&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BMS 240, BMS241 and BMS352&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;teaching-staff&quot;&gt;Teaching staff&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wouter Kalle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feedback is one of the most important aspects in student learning and traditionally scores quite low in the SES scores at CSU. An initiative in the UK called the &lt;em&gt;audio supported enhanced learning support project&lt;/em&gt; (Stewart 2008) set out to use technology to enhance and personalise teaching. A study in the USA found that using audio feedback was faster than written feedback but the quality of the feedback increased at least 2-fold ((Ice, Curtis, Phillips, &amp;amp; Wells, 2007). Whilst this is not the place to give a full review on the benefits of audio feedback, there is widespread agreement in the literature that audio feedback is a superior form of feedback which will enhance learning and teaching (Dickson, 2015)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However another maybe even more important aspect of audio feedback is the opportunity to provide a more personal connection with the student which could lead to more engagement of the students with their subject, their course and even the university (Rowe 2011). Studies have shown an increased ability to understand the feedback, as there is more nuance and intonation and greater feelings of subject involvement especially in distance education (Oleseva and Richardson 2011). All this means that audio feedback can provide a system to create greater personal contact and maybe even emotional support (Rowe 2011). This shows that this type of feedback could be an extremely useful tool to increase subject engagement and student retention in online programs at CSU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;implementation&quot;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Briefly, the audio feedback system is set up as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assignments are downloaded from EASTS website on the due date.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the text different coloured highlights are made and if necessary comments are created using MS-word.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using MS-Word, the criteria are pasted in front of the assignment and the levels attained are highlighted and marks are awarded to each separate criterion.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Final marks are recorded in spreadsheet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using a very simple Apple Mac app (called lecture recorder) and the computer microphone audio feedback is recorded for the student. The student’s first name is used and both the criteria and marks, are discussed.  The various highlights and comments in the text are explained.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The recording is usually between 3 minutes (very good marks, HD level) and 7 minutes (lots of remarks, usually PS/CR level).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marked files are sent back to the students through EASTS to record return date&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An email is sent to the students using the EASTS handing-in email containing the marked file and the audio file. This ‘double-up’ is done as the linking of the audio file to the marked document does not work very well and sometimes the audio file gets lost in the EASTS transition. Also this is a point of Quality Control to check whether all assignments have been marked and marks recorded.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quality Control is ensured by using the original file names for the audio files and consistently using student numbers and student names to record audio feedback and marks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The audio feedback always flows according to a fixed pattern. Below is an excerpt of a typical audio feedback file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Good morning (students first name), I just wanted to give you some audio feedback on your (subject code) assignment. As you can see I have copied and pasted the criteria in front of your work and blocked out the levels you have attained in pink. I added up all the marks and you scored X marks out of a hundred”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A description of the levels attained follows including an explanation why these were attained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Looking at your assignment I have highlighted some parts which will be discussed now”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The highlights are in different colours depending on whether they are regarding content, grammar, referencing or general. An explanation of the highlights and comments follows while slowly going through the text. According to personal feedback, students can actually follow the marking and comments through the text and are never lost. The audio feedback always ends with a conclusion and some words of encouragement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“In short, you have achieved X marks, if you would pay attention to (a brief repeat of previous comments) you would easily score a (higher) level. I really enjoyed reading and marking your assignment and looking forward to seeing more of your work”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guide&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking to implementing completely online marking within your subject/s, there are some important considerations to make when planning this approach:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consider the platform most suitable for your cohort and the assessment task.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The virtues of audio feedback (like any feedback) seem to lay mostly in the detail of the feedback, the guidance it gives to increase quality in future work, the personal touch it gives and the idea of connection to the subject and university as is shown in the above comments and the many emails on the topic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EASTS, NORFOLK (or voice recording app)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;literature&quot;&gt;Literature&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;apa-ref&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Boud, D. and Associates (2010). &lt;em&gt;Assessment 2020: Seven propositions for assessment reform in higher education&lt;/em&gt;. Sydney: Australian Learning and Teaching Council&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Dickson S. (2015) The pastoral potential of audio feedback: a review of the literature. &lt;em&gt;Pastoral Care in Education, 33:2&lt;/em&gt;, 96-104&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Henderson, M., &amp;amp; Phillips, M. (2015). Video-based feedback on student assessment: scarily personal. &lt;em&gt;Australasian Journal of Educational Technology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Ice, P., Curtis, R., Phillips, P., &amp;amp; Wells, J. (2007). Using asynchronous audio feedback to enhance teaching presence and students’ sense of community. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Asynchronous Learning Networks, 11&lt;/em&gt;, 3–26.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Olesova, L., &amp;amp; Richardson, J. (2011). Using asynchronous instructional audio feedback in online environments: A mixed methods study. &lt;em&gt;MERLOT Journal of Online Learning and Teaching, 7&lt;/em&gt;, 30–42.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Rowe, A. (2011). The personal dimension in teaching: Why students value feedback. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Educational Management, 25&lt;/em&gt;, 343–360.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Stewart, W. (2008). ASEL project plan. JISC. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jisc.ac.uk/media/documents/programmes/usersandinnovation/aselplan.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.jisc.ac.uk/media/documents/programmes/usersandinnovation/aselplan.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 10:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>/csulx/strategy/online-marking-effective-feedback.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/csulx/strategy/online-marking-effective-feedback.html</guid>
        
        <category>Interactive Resources</category>
        
        <category>E-Assessment</category>
        
        
        <category>strategy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome Videos</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A welcome video of between 5-10 minutes can be used at the commencement of a new subject by the academic/instructor to provide aspects such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introductory information about the subject such as how it fits in with the students wider course that the student is completing-e.g. What prior learning it builds upon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clarify early concerns that the academic suspects students might hold based on his/her prior experience in delivering the subject-for example the academic might flag that students need to consider completing a pre-requisite subject&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Makes clear the primary methods of communication that will be utilised throughout the subject&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;provides students some introductory background regarding the academic’s experience and background in this field of study, giving students a sense of confidence&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highlight key aspects of the assessment for the subject and key teaching and learning information&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gives students some insight into interests or hobbies etc in order to position themselves as someone who is also managing the demands of work, study and life and which provides an opening for students to themselves provide some some information which can help form the basis of deeper engagement when studying online.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;engagement&quot;&gt;Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of a welcome video, available before or at the start of session helps a student establish the context for the teaching, learning and assessment that will occur in the subject. Providing this information in a video, instead of solely relying on a text-based approach, helps students more readily identify with the academic. Providing a welcome video which clearly articulates expectations and highlights the important aspects of the subject can be a foundation to increasing learner-to-academic interaction, this being a key aspect in increasing learner engagement. Research such as that carried out as part of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lowses.edu.au/assets/ALTC%20LSES%20Final%20Report%202012.pdf&quot;&gt;LSES report&lt;/a&gt; clearly highlights the need for students, particularly those from non traditional backgrounds, to be able to feel that their lecturers are approachable and support their learning journey. Providing a welcome video is an important part of the strategy mix in achieving these aims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guide&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create a successful Welcome Video there are some decisions to make:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t try to explain every topic/week within the video - focus on aspects such as summarising the learning outcomes and describing the assessment tasks in conjunction with details that will allow students to make a successful commencement to the subject. The intention should be to welcome students and complement the information that is already available to them. To that end, prioritise the key messages you want students to know when they finish your welcome video.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consider the context of the video - can you get creative and record the video in a location other than your office? For example, for a science subject, could you record the welcome video in the lab? Getting a colleague to assist you to record via e.g. smartphone in a genuine setting is at least as powerful for students as a click through powerpoint with voiceover, and your enthusiasm for the subject will be readily apparent to students.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The creation of a welcome video need not be onerous - rather than creating a start to finish ‘script’, an equally useful approach is to create a series of headings with supporting ‘talking points.’ A ‘welcome’ video will potentially feel more welcoming if it is relatively informal and accessible, with just the key aspects conveyed to students. Equally important is the fact that you needn’t feel compelled to have every latest feature in your video production - a simply delivered clear message that students can identify with is more than adequate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Think about how your use of a welcome video fits in with your broader plan to build and maintain your teacher presence and how you will communicate with students throughout the subject. Successful student communication is relevant, timely and accessible. Your communication approach shouldn’t be a moving target for students-in other words, utilising a smaller range of communication strategies in an effective and efficient way means greater consistency and provides one less barrier for success for online learners who will quickly learn where and how you communicate-a trait online students appreciate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create a welcome video there is a wide variety of tools available, many of them CSU supported technologies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CSU Replay/Personal Capture&lt;/strong&gt; (Echo360) - useful when you wish to capture both yourself as a ‘talking head’ in conjunction with what you are presenting. Of course this software provides options such as voice capture with screen only. A useful tool because the start to finish process can be handled from your desktop;it’s a CSU supported technology and provides ease of insertion into your subject space within interact2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adobe Connect&lt;/strong&gt; - used primarily within CSU as a meeting tool, but does provide a screenshare and recording functionality-particularly useful if you intend on providing a recording of an online meeting you have run as a ‘Welcome’ type meeting at the start of your subject.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Computer webcams&lt;/strong&gt; - you can create a direct to camera recording utilising the webcam and microphone on your desktop/laptop (PC or mac) and there a numerous options for making this available e.g. storing and streaming in youtube as a private channel and embedding in your interact2 homepage or uploading the file into i2 as well (not recommended as students will incur greater download charges).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile technologies&lt;/strong&gt; - such as ipads and smartphones can provide you with a quick and easy way to capture footage ‘in the real world.’ Be aware that these files can quickly become large in size and emailing as a means of moving files can quickly degrade the quality, rendering them unusable. The best way to move these files is through a cloud storage solution such as google drive or dropbox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;apa-ref&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Borup, J., West, R. E., &amp;amp; Graham, C. R. (2012). Improving online social presence through asynchronous video. &lt;em&gt;The Internet and Higher Education&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt;15&lt;/em&gt;(3), 195-203.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 10:22:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>/csulx/strategy/welcome-videos.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/csulx/strategy/welcome-videos.html</guid>
        
        <category>Learning Communities</category>
        
        <category>Teacher Presence</category>
        
        
        <category>strategy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reflective Journals</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reflection is an internal dialogue facilitated by writing and creative strategies as a way of expressing, sharing, assessing and developing professional experience. By recognising and taking responsibility for personal and professional identity, values, action and feelings the student undertaking reflection within the constructs of a subject or course is demonstrating a willingness to stay with uncertainty, doubt and questioning in order to engage in spirited enquiry leading to constructive developmental change and professional integrity based on deep understanding. Knowing what to reflect upon is as critical a part of the educative process as the reflection action itself, and is a pedagogical approach that draws in reflective practice and reflexivity - finding strategies to question attitudes, values and limits of personal knowledge. A key area in the development of the professional practitioner is the ability to reflect on practise as part of the process of learning in order to foster continuous professional growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital reflective journals are part of a pedagogically enriched learning design within online or technology-rich context to support and improve learning experiences. A reflective journal is also especially useful for assessing intended learning outcomes  relating to the application of content knowledge, professional judgement and reflection on past decisions and problem solving, with a view to improving them. Reflective thinking also helps students develop a questioning attitude and new perspective; identify areas for change and improvement; respond effectively to challenges; and generalise and apply what they have learned from one situation to other situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to online learning students need time to locate their new learning within framework of their subject or course, and academics as teachers need to support and nurture learners to learn within the same connected and collaborative learning environments as teaching takes place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;engagement&quot;&gt;Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A digital reflective journal written as a blog provides students with the freedom to engage with content, ideas, discoveries, disappointments, or  to simply ponder their learning. Online learning journals should be open and shared spaces, ready for enjoyment as well as providing an opportunity for students to demonstrate functioning knowledge.  Part of the engagement is being able to share with others in the cohort, as a participatory learning experience, and to make use of  (or learn how to) leverage the affordances of online platforms to better engage with  content or  leverage available resources to communicate thoughts, discoveries, academic reflections, and multimedia artefacts. Students are also able to demonstrate learning through multimodal additions to the online reflective journal.  A reflective journal provides a flexible and responsive way to share the joy of learning!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-practice&quot;&gt;In Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;subject&quot;&gt;Subject&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;INF530 Concepts and practices in a digital age&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;teaching-staff&quot;&gt;Teaching staff&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Judy O’Connell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This keystone subject establishes the reflective journal process for use within the subject, but more particularly within the whole course. Students are encouraged to extend themselves by peer responses to their work, and are motivated to explore and embrace the affordances of the online environment to explore their knowledge and share their experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;implementation&quot;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CSU Thinkspace provided the ideal vehicle for transforming learning experiences through the use of a reflective journal. Using a CSU username and password students are introduced to a platform that has full flexibility for customisation to reflect personal preferences and provide a touch of motivation. Importantly this is also linked to a range of  formative steps supported by the academic in building knowledge and understanding:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Key topics for reflection&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peer-to-peer responses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Teacher feedback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Literacy and communication&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Celebration of learning achievements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I found the blogging aspect really helpful to make connections and illustrate my learning to myself and others.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“HAVING to create a professional blog - helpful for me to clarify and reflect on my learning throughout this subject; and great to be able to share my classmates learning via their blogs too.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guide&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In looking for opportunities to develop and offer students an opportunity to engage in reflective journalling there are a range of considerations that need to be made:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reflective journals provide an opportunity for students to explore, ask questions, respond to readings, summarize key ideas, recognise strengths and weaknesses in their emerging professional understanding and/or practice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understand why you are introducing this strategy. Reflective journals can be a powerful way to build understanding while also providing a responsive mechanism for personalisation of the learning process. However the process is unlikely to be nurtured by introducing too many compulsory posts, tight timelines, or other artificial constraints particularly where there is no teacher presence visible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consider your strategy for  engaging interaction between students, in order to build community while also fostering a capacity for personal autonomy and accountability in the process of knowledge networking. Link the reflective journal activity to connected learning experiences or elements of professional practice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a decision about the contextual setting of your reflective journal activities.  Will your cohort be working in Interact2 in a ‘closed’ learner-community space, or will your cohort be working in open, collaborative public spaces engaging with the cohort and beyond with the discipline and/or profession?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All forms of online learning journals are valuable, but should be designed to best support the required participatory experiences of individual subjects or courses.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is best not to ask students to cut and paste blog posts and place them into a discussion forum, or vice versa. However, some students do like to share the depth of their growing ideas and understanding,  and how they do this in relation to a reflective journal post is up to them or your class structures. For example, students can provide a link to their post via Twitter and the subject hashtag, or perhaps begin a discussion forum post with “I have just written a post about….” providing a linked URL and commenting on why that post has been important to their emerging understanding relevant to the Discussion forum.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An online journal post can extend on, or allow deeper personal deliberation of content emerging in the class discussion forum.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work may be formative or summative, therefore careful consideration of the learning design of the subject and/or course is essential&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CSU Thinkspace; PebblePad; Interact2 blog; other online platforms&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;apa-ref&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Bull, G., Thompson, A., Searson, M., Garafalo, J., Park, J., Young, C., et al, (2008). Connecting informal and formal learning experiences in the age of participatory media. &lt;em&gt;Contemporary issues in technology and teacher education&lt;/em&gt;, 8(2), 100-107.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Cho, M. H., &amp;amp; Kim, B. J. (2013). Students’ self-regulation for interaction with others in online learning environments. &lt;em&gt;The Internet and Higher Education&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;17&lt;/em&gt;, 69-75.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Garrison, D.R. (2015). &lt;em&gt;Thinking collaboratively: Learning in a community of enquiry&lt;/em&gt;. London: Taylor &amp;amp; Francis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 10:14:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>/csulx/strategy/reflective-journals.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/csulx/strategy/reflective-journals.html</guid>
        
        <category>Interaction Between Students</category>
        
        <category>Interaction with the Professions</category>
        
        
        <category>strategy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Simulations &amp; Exploratory Learning</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simulation and exploratory learning provide ways for students to interact with environments and situations that mimic the real world. Students can be immersed in both highly realistic environments and situations that mirror those they may encounter in their profession. Simulations also provide a unique ability to recreate dangerous environments, these give students an opportunity to make mistakes as part of the learning process without harmful personal or real-world consequences. The ability to explore these actions and their consequences provide rich individual learning experiences or if  working with others, have the opportunity to discuss the options and recalibrate your thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;engagement&quot;&gt;Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through active learning students take their knowledge to the next step and incorporate it into practice. Simulations can provide deep and profound learning opportunities for students by challenging their knowledge, skill and competency in realistic and authentic situations. They are required to bring together theory and practice in a demonstrable way. Encouraging students to do this in groups and with one another can assist students develop a clear sense of the importance of peer-to-peer learning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guide&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simulation and exploratory learning environments are often time consuming and difficult to set up and as a consequence their use is currently limited, but that is changing as new and emerging technologies provide simpler ways to author and create simulations. One way to get the development hurdle is to piggyback simulations onto existing platforms, software and games to focus efforts on the purpose of the simulation. Their use as a learning resource can be quite profound because of the direct interaction occurring between the student and the computer model and their ability to directly see the consequences of their actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools like Adobe Captivate and Smart Sparrow provide simple ways of creating branching scenarios and can utilise existing tools like Powerpoint to design and create the visual elements. Smart Sparrow also includes a rules engine that can create quite in depth interactions based on choices and interactions that the student performs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;apa-ref&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wills, S. (2012). The Simulation Triad. In C. Nygaard, N. Courtney &amp;amp; E. Leigh (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Simulations, Games and Role Play in University Education&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 23-40). Faringdon, UK: Libri.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 10:03:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>/csulx/strategy/simulations-exploratory-learning.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/csulx/strategy/simulations-exploratory-learning.html</guid>
        
        <category>Interaction Between Students</category>
        
        <category>Interaction with the Professions</category>
        
        <category>Flexible &amp; Adaptive Learning</category>
        
        <category>Interactive Resources</category>
        
        <category>E-Assessment</category>
        
        
        <category>strategy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Role play</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Role plays are situations in which learners take on the profiles of specific characters or representatives in a contrived setting. Role plays are designed primarily to build first-person experiences within safe environments (Wills, Leigh, Ip &amp;amp; Albert, 2011, p. 17). By providing students with realistic scenarios similar to those they may experience in the workplace, students are able to solve problems and consider different perspectives while collaborating with classmates. This is consistent with Herrington’s description of ‘cognitive reality’ (Herrington et al., 2009, p. 45). In such situations, students are able to apply new knowledge and develop skills needed for the real world. Role play is widely acknowledged to be a powerful teaching technique in face-to-face, blended and online settings and has been singled out as an example of good practice by the Australian Learning and Teaching Council (UoW, 2003).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;engagement&quot;&gt;Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Student engage with each other in assumed roles. It could be argued that being online makes this easier for the students, and infact the idea of an online ‘persona’ is somewhat empowering. Students also engage with the content in a proactive manner and must demonstrate judgement and professional behaviours based upon their learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-practice&quot;&gt;In Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;subject&quot;&gt;Subject&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;INR503&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;teaching-staff&quot;&gt;Teaching staff&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lynnette Ainsworth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To develop students professional readiness through engagement in authentic learning experiences based on current topics and relevance to industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;implementation&quot;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Student enrolled in &lt;em&gt;INR503 Industrial Relations Practice&lt;/em&gt; work within small groups of 6 to 8, each student assumes a professional role - a company representative, union representative, employee representative, HR manager, HR assistant or industry representative. The class is given an Enterprise Bargaining Agreement midway through the session and the roleplay consists of the negotiation process. Lasting around three weeks, after which students reflect upon the process and write an individual, critical analysis as their summative assessment task. There is a minor, less formal group presentation in which each team shares their experiences via an Online meeting tutorial. Students utilise i2 Organisation sites act to act as virtual ‘study rooms’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guide&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some useful ideas / advice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once one Org site is set-up it can be easily duplicated to accommodate all teams.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At the end of session, there may be student artefact which are useful for the next session&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is suggested that such activities are conducted later in the session when students are less likely to drop a subject and relationships between students may already be established.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use the main teaching site to brief all students collectively and to debrief at the end of the activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the individual Organisation sites, links to relevant professional websites appear within the left-hand vertical navigation. Information relating to the task is presented in clearly labeled resources folders (including Enterprise Bargaining Agreement to be resolved) i2 tools are provided (async and synchronous) which include: Online meeting, announcement, discussion board. A resources folder is set-up for each role, so each student has his/her own space for sharing documents or recording their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;apa-ref&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Herrington, J., Reeves, T., &amp;amp; Oliver, R. (2009). &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csuau.eblib.com.ezproxy.csu.edu.au/patron/FullRecord.aspx?p=465326&quot;&gt;A practical guide to authentic e-learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Retrieved from EBL collection&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Palloff, R. &amp;amp; Pratt, K. (2010). &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csuau.eblib.com.ezproxy.csu.edu.au/patron/FullRecord.aspx?p=529967&quot;&gt;Collaborating online: Learning together in community&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Retrieved from EBook Library&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wills, S., Leigh, S. &amp;amp; Ip, A. (2011) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csuau.eblib.com.ezproxy.csu.edu.au/patron/Read.aspx?p=668307&amp;amp;pg=32&quot;&gt;Games, simulation and role plays&lt;/a&gt;. In &lt;em&gt;The power of role-based elearning: Designing and moderating&lt;/em&gt; Retrieved from EBL collection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 10:03:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>/csulx/strategy/role-play.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/csulx/strategy/role-play.html</guid>
        
        <category>Learning Communities</category>
        
        <category>Interaction Between Students</category>
        
        <category>Teacher Presence</category>
        
        <category>Interaction with the Professions</category>
        
        
        <category>strategy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Collaborative Group Projects</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collaborative Group Projects are learning experiences designed to foster student interaction in order to achieve a shared goal - in many circumstances linked to assessment. These experiences are normally task based and more formal than e.g. ad hoc study groups. Group projects can take place in many circumstances and are often linked to a deeper level of instructional design and andragogy such as Project or Problem Based Learning or Scenario based learning. Collaborative Group Projects offer a range of benefits to students including utilisation and development of vital pre-professional skills, problem solving and collaborative skills and perhaps most importantly, students are provided with a source of ongoing feedback from peers, which can be a valuable source of learning and development for these students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;engagement&quot;&gt;Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inclusion of a collaborative group project provides a range of affordances which can lead to deeper engagement for online and distance education students. First among these is that such tasks provide students with the chance to interact with others, potentially lessening the sense of isolation and perceived ‘distance’ between themselves and other students, the lecturer and the wider institution. Students can benefit from the chance to learn and express views in a smaller group, giving students the chance to learn in a more active way when compared to many individually based tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-practice&quot;&gt;In Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;subject&quot;&gt;Subject&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ITC105&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;teaching-staff&quot;&gt;Teaching staff&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anthony Chan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a communication subject, the learning activity was designed to help students share their work, their communication skills and further develop their own ideas on how to best respond to a workplace scenario, whilst developing digital literacy skills using Cloud services, and cooperative learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;implementation&quot;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subject coordinator set up a shared Google Drive and Docs space for the students to access via a shared link. The students were provided with a workplace scenario on a disgruntled customer. Each student had to write a response to the customer using the Google Docs, enabling all students to view each other’s work. They provided comments and ideas for each other as well. Student were able to share their communication ideas, strategies and expression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guide&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In looking for opportunities to develop and offer students an online collaborative group project, there are a range of considerations that need to be made:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understand the ‘why.’ Chances are that many of your students are juggling the demands of life-work, study, family and social commitments. Be clear on the reasons why you want students to collaborate. Is this group collaboration going to improve their content knowledge or skills? Increase their ability to act in a professional or collegial manner or support attainment of one of CSU’s Graduate Learning Outcomes? Be linked to, or be the actual assessment task? Lived experiences suggest that offering collaborative group tasks without a very clear link to assessment and associated outcomes, prove to have very low levels of student engagement.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Authenticity - the group collaboration you’re planning should reflect some kind of real world task, issue or circumstance as relating to the discipline or profession in question. In some circumstances there may be scope to move from a scenario to real world project, the outcomes of which will be applicable in some way to a wider audience or issue beyond the university. Regardless, a measure of realism will help build and maintain student interest.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practicality - Along with understanding why you want students to collaborate and what the substance of the collaborative efforts will be, it is equally important to consider how practical it is for your students to collaborate. Are you expecting your students to collaborate ‘in real time’ i.e. ‘synchronously’ or is it ok for them to complete their roles at a time that suits them i.e. ‘asynchronously.’ For example, expecting postgraduate shift working nurses to collaborate at the same time on a group task in an online meeting might be a much harder logistical exercise than first year undergraduate students. Is what you are intending to offer feasible for students to complete?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Collaboration - implies that the end result will not just be a compilation of individual work put together (typified by students ‘doing their part’) but that there is collective effort in creating a body of work that is representative of a genuine exchange of ideas and co-creation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assessment - considering how you will assess collaborative group work is important-will the group receive one mark or will individual members receive a mark as well? If so, what evidence will you rely upon to assign each mark-peer assessments, reflective tasks, journals and blogs and tracking of individual work input are all potential strategies, each with their own factors to consider.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roles and Responsibilities-depending on the underlying andragogical and instructional design approach, e.g. ‘Problem Based Learning’ you may need to articulate the roles within a group and model and provide ongoing support for students as they fulfill these roles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a wide variety of tools available to support the implementation of Collaborative Group Projects, many of them CSU supported technologies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adobe Connect Meeting Rooms - students can be offered their own adobe connect meeting room to collaborate on projects, with the added advantage that these meetings can be recorded. There are a range of useful approaches such as creating a layout for each stage of collaboration, which help track student involvement and participation. There are some limitations however, including the need to ensure that students have correct access permissions to edit their room layouts (or you will need to pre-design useful layouts for each group, which can be done as a bulk process).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CSU Interact-various functionalities-our learning management system, interact2, provides a ‘Group tool’ which has a range of functionalities such as a wiki, group discussion forums, file exchanges etc. Interact2 is a good solution for collaborative group work if this collaboration is primarily text based, and can be used as a centralised area for the group to organise themselves.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Docs-ease of access and a wide range of functionality within the google environment make it a useful tool for group collaboration, including the ability to have multiple editors working on a document simultaneously. Students can use features such as ‘hangouts’ to connect via video chat to collaborate within this space. It is important to note that as this is not an officially supported teaching and learning tool, CSU cannot ensure integrity-e.g.work lost or deleted in this space cannot be retrieved. Use of these third party services generally involves students signing up to create an account.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video Conferencing Technologies - Skype, CSU video conferencing system - there are many choices available-circumstances dictate which way students will collaborate-&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Discipline/profession specific collaboration tools-too many to list, but ensuring that students have appropriate access privileges by organising with the software vendor well ahead of the teaching and learning session is an appropriate design step&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When planning and offering best practice is to provide a reliable, supported ‘default’ approach as well as articulating and modelling a range of ways in which collaboration can enriched-hopefully the default is also a best practice! There should be easy to access and understand help guides (text/audio/video) available for students so that they can trouble shoot minor problems themselves. If not, the creation of simple ‘how to guides’ may make your experience of facilitating Collaborative Group Projects all the more fruitful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;apa-ref&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Hiltz, Starr Roxanne. (1997). &lt;em&gt;Impacts of college - level courses via Asynchronous Learning Networks: Some Preliminary Results&lt;/em&gt;. Journal of Asynchronous Learning Networks. 1(2).&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Slavin, R. (1996). Research on Cooperative Learning and Achievement: What We Know, What We Need to Know. &lt;em&gt;Contemporary Educational Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 21, 43–69.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wallace, R. M. (2003). Online learning in higher education: A review of research on interactions among teachers and students. &lt;em&gt;Education, Communication &amp;amp; Information, 3&lt;/em&gt;(2), 241-280.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 10:03:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>/csulx/strategy/collaborative-group-projects.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/csulx/strategy/collaborative-group-projects.html</guid>
        
        <category>Learning Communities</category>
        
        <category>Interaction Between Students</category>
        
        <category>E-Assessment</category>
        
        
        <category>strategy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Asynchronous Discussions</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asynchronous discussions are tasks that students can access and engage with at anytime, they do not have to be on their computer at a set time or in a set place. Asynchronous discussions are specifically designed to be flexible and are able to be engaged with at anytime in order to fit into the student’s study schedule, be it midday or midnight. These discussion can be made compulsory and tied to assessment tasks or optional and act as a support tool for students. Like all discussion tasks they need to have a specific purpose or discussion point in order to motivate students. While traditionally text based discussion forums have been the tool of choice,  there are a range of new tools that utilise rich media such as video and audio to facilitate these discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;engagement&quot;&gt;Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Providing asynchronous discussion opportunities from your students is an essential element of the Online/DE learning experience for all CSU students. If students are engaged with &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; as the teacher, and engaged with &lt;em&gt;peers&lt;/em&gt; as learning colleagues, they are far more likely to participate and contribute, and achieve better results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, ensuring that all subjects provide Asynchronous discussion opportunities is essential given the needs of our students whilst completing their degree. So many CSU Online students work part-time or even full time, are caring for children or sick relatives, or even travelling abroad for work. Students cannot always participate in the synchronous Online Meetings so they need suitable asynchronous engagement opportunities to integrate with their individual study schedules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-practice&quot;&gt;In Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;subject&quot;&gt;Subject&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EMT409&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;teaching-staff&quot;&gt;Teaching Staff&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alissa Brabin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the Course, students were indicating they had minimal social interaction between themselves, and limited use of online tools. This subject was redesigned to focus on developing social presence, interaction between students and sharing of ideas and developing a Community of Practice (CoP). The early assessments and learning tasks were also designed as a stepping stone for developing a CoP as required in Assessment 3. Students reported that after 2 years of studying part-time as a cohort, this was the first time they had actually heard or seen each other!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;implementation&quot;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lecturer used FlipGrid to provide short video updates to students throughout the session that were then embedded in the Home Page. FlipGrid was also used for assessment purposes for students to introduce themselves to the class and to engage students in a discussion about their own experiences with technology. There were only 46 students in this class but some of these videos had over 2000 views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../images/flip-grid.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guide&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be clear about the use of the tool as well as the question or focus of the activity. Linking discussions to Assessment provides an extrinsic motivation and can be a key strategy to encourage student participation. Be sure to make the engagement opportunities simple for student to access by providing embedded links to reduce the navigation required to find the point of engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different tools have different affordances and can be used in quite different ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discussion Forums&lt;/strong&gt; - Set up Forums with specific and structured questions designed for open discussion amongst students. Highlight recent events / current issues as applicable to real world practice. Academic may need to lead/closely monitor for the first 2-3 but aim for student lead discussion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blogs&lt;/strong&gt; - Ideally suited for summative assessments. If students are able to see and comment on each other’s work, they are more likely to engage due to the inherent benefit that a CoP offers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recordings of Online Meetings&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; record Online Meetings and always provide the link to students. Those who could not attend are then given the chance to benefit from the interaction and questions of their peers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FlipGrip&lt;/strong&gt; - Allows the academic to ask a question or present discussion topic, and students create a 90 second video response using the URL provided. Easy and highly effective tool for developing a sense of community amongst learners by allowing them to see and hear each other. Videos embed easily into i2 pages. Flipgrid has a $60 annual fee for staff to create and use grids but is free for students to access and use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a wide variety of tools available to support the implementation of Asynchronous Discussions, many of them CSU supported technologies including Interact2 Discussion Forums, Blogs and Online Meetings. External technologies could include &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flipgrid.com&quot;&gt;FlipGrip&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://cel.ly/&quot;&gt;Celly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;apa-ref&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Aragon, S (2003). Creating Social Presence in Online Environments. &lt;em&gt;New Directions for Adult and Continuing Education&lt;/em&gt;, (100) pp. 57-68.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Boud, D., Cohen, R., &amp;amp; Sampson, J. (Eds.). (2014). &lt;em&gt;Peer learning in higher education: Learning from and with each other&lt;/em&gt;. Routledge&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Karel Kreijnsa, Paul A. Kirschnerb, Wim Jochemsb (2003). Identifying the pitfalls for social interaction in computer-supported collaborative learning environments: a review of the research. &lt;em&gt;Computers in Human Behavior&lt;/em&gt; (19). pp. 335–353.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;McLoughlin, C. &amp;amp; Lee, M.J.W. (2010). Developing an online community to promote engagement and professional learning for pre-service teachers using social software tools. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Cases in Information Technology, 12&lt;/em&gt;(1), 17-30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 10:03:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>/csulx/strategy/asynchronous-discussions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/csulx/strategy/asynchronous-discussions.html</guid>
        
        <category>Learning Communities</category>
        
        <category>Interaction Between Students</category>
        
        <category>Teacher Presence</category>
        
        
        <category>strategy</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
