<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CSU Online Learning Exchange</title>
    <description>Developed and Maintained by Charles Sturt University's u!magine</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/csulx/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/csulx/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 17:20:39 +1100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 17:20:39 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Role Play</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Role plays are situations in which learners take on the profiles of specific characters or representatives in a contrived setting. Role plays are designed primarily to build first-person experiences within safe environments (Wills, Leigh, Ip &amp;amp; Albert, 2011, p. 17). They can also be utilised with groups of students to develop empathy and understanding of the different relationships and situations they may encounter. By providing students with realistic scenarios, similar to those in the workplace, students are able to solve problems and consider different perspectives while collaborating with classmates. This is consistent with Herrington’s description of ‘cognitive reality’ (Herrington et al., 2009, p. 45) where students are able to apply new knowledge and develop skills needed for the real world. Role play is widely acknowledged to be a powerful teaching technique in face-to-face, blended and online settings and has been singled out as an example of good practice by the Australian Learning and Teaching Council (UoW, 2003).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;engagement&quot;&gt;Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students work with each other in assumed roles which leads to deeper engagement and understanding of both the content and professional practice. It can be argued that being online makes this easier for the students. Some go so far as to describe the online persona as an empowering experience. Within role plays, students have the opportunity to behave in a  more proactive manner and must demonstrate judgement and professional behaviours based upon their learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-practice&quot;&gt;In Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;subject&quot;&gt;Subject&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;INR503: Industrial Relations Practice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;teaching-staff&quot;&gt;Teaching Staff&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lynnette Ainsworth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To develop students professional readiness through engagement in authentic learning experiences based on current topics and relevance to industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;implementation&quot;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students enrolled in &lt;em&gt;INR503 Industrial Relations Practice&lt;/em&gt; work within small groups of 6 to 8.  Each student assumes a professional role - a company representative, union representative, employee representative, HR manager, HR assistant or industry representative. The class is given an enterprise bargaining agreement midway through the session. This sets the scene, as each group of students must negotiate a new agreement.  Based upon the negotiation process, the role play lasts around three weeks. Once completed each student reflects upon the process and writes a critical analysis.  This is a major summative assessment task. There is a minor, less formal group presentation in which each team shares their experiences via an online meeting tutorial.  This also serves as a debriefing session and allows for peer feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../images/practices/RolePlay-INR503.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Roleplay Screenshot&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guide&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Role plays provide a unique way for students to engage with and practice their learning. The situations, scenarios and roles require an element of planning, but can be garnered from case studies. Roles and situations can be controlled by placing limits on the scenario and scope, but students could also be provided with more freedom to explore the scenario, roles and interactions.  Some useful ideas/advice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conducting role plays later in the session means that students are less likely to dropout which can disturb the group dynamics and it allows time for relationships between students to be established.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide students with a briefing document that outlines the scenario and clearly states the objectives and constraints of the activity.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Things don’t always go to plan so ensure that you provide students with a way to debrief and discuss what happened. This can be a valuable learning opportunity in itself, and provides students with a chance to be reflective of their own practice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interact2 can provide an excellent basis for role play. By utilising the resources folder, announcements and discussion boards, lecturers are able to provide students with information and space for discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lecturers are encouraged to give each group (role play team) an Interact 2 Organisation site in which to conduct their role play as well as communicate among themselves. This is a relatively easy task in that Organisation sites can be copied to accommodate the number of students/role play teams per session. The inclusion of online meeting rooms for real time and synchronous discussion is highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;apa-ref&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Herrington, J., Reeves, T., &amp;amp; Oliver, R. (2009). *A practical guide to authentic e-learning. * Retrieved from EBL collection.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Palloff, R. &amp;amp; Pratt, K. (2010). &lt;em&gt;Collaborating online: Learning together in community.&lt;/em&gt; Retrieved from EBook Library.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wills, S., Leigh, S. &amp;amp; Ip, A. (2011) Games, simulation and role plays. In &lt;em&gt;The power of role-based elearning: Designing and moderating.&lt;/em&gt; Retrieved from EBL collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 15:15:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/csulx/strategy/role-play.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/csulx/strategy/role-play.html</guid>
        
        <category>Learning Communities</category>
        
        <category>Interaction Between Students</category>
        
        <category>Interaction with the Professions</category>
        
        
        <category>strategy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Social Media Streams</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social Media provides an incredibly powerful tool for learning and teaching. It enables real-time communication, sharing and dialogue to occur at a global level. The streams created by social media provide a realtime way of publishing and accessing information relevant to students learning. Educators can use social media streams to promote their learning and professional communities of practice by sharing interesting stories or news relating to course work. Social media streams provide an opportunity for substantial collective thinking and action (NMC, 2014).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;engagement&quot;&gt;Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media streams provide a way to publish, collect and curate information in real-time. Social media itself allows students to engage in a variety of ways, with not only lecturers and peers but with individuals, professionals and experts worldwide. This contextualises study beyond the University, reflecting the broader profession and global setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-practice&quot;&gt;In Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;subject&quot;&gt;Subject&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;INF530: Concepts and Practices for a Digital Age&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;teaching-staff&quot;&gt;Teaching Staff&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Judy O’Connell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media and networking tools are used to connect all cohorts within the course and promote ongoing dialogue, sharing of resources and the development of professional presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;implementation&quot;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course- level site (Knowledge Networks and Digital Innovation) was served as a portal, housing links to individual subjects as well as a Twitter feed, Thinkspace login (ePortfolio, blogging tool) and Diigo (social bookmarking).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;container row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;offset-by-two eight columns&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;swiper-container&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;swiper-wrapper image-container&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;swiper-slide&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/practices/social-media-INF530-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;twitter screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;swiper-slide&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/practices/social-media-INF530-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;twitter screenshot&quot; /&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;swiper-slide&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/practices/social-media-INF530-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;twitter screenshot&quot; /&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;swiper-slide&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/practices/social-media-INF530-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;twitter screenshot&quot; /&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;swiper-pagination&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;swiper-button-next&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;swiper-button-prev&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guide&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media is an incredibly powerful tool that allows student work to be published to a global audience and enable dialogue between students, educators, university staff, professional and experts, in a less formal and more immediate form. Utilising hashtags and creating specialised accounts to harness social media streams means that the learning community as a whole can benefit from the wealth of information available. They provide a way to structure and share interactions, thoughts, ideas and relevant information. While each platform can be used on it’s own the streams created can often be embedded into course and organisational sites in Interact2, providing students with a simple way of interacting and engaging. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://cms.drupal.ku.edu/how-embed-facebook-feed&quot;&gt;How to Embed Facebook Feed&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://elearn.southampton.ac.uk/blackboard/addtwitter/&quot;&gt;How to Embed Twitter Feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As education aligns more closely with technological trends, lecturers need to carefully consider the use of social media for teaching and learning purposes. Students will often set up their own Facebook groups, but whether or not lecturers use social media in their teaching is another matter. It is recommended they consider the appropriateness and desired outcomes when using social media and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g_is3gT7X0Y&quot;&gt;the affordances of the different platforms&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://policy.csu.edu.au/view.current.php?id=00384&quot;&gt;CSU’s Social media use policy for staff&lt;/a&gt; is also worth perusing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomayess’ 2015 examination of social media use within Australian higher education identifies clear advantages and disadvantages. While in general terms social media and networking tools can improve students’ personal and professional skills such as writing, speaking, listening, discussion and debating, she goes on to argue that the risks should be considered from four perspectives: cognitive development, social development, physical development and security (Tomayess, 2015, p. 18).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several social media and networking tools to choose from and in this short video &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g_is3gT7X0Y&quot;&gt;Harold Jarche discusses some of the differences between the social media platforms&lt;/a&gt;. Facebook, Twitter, Instagram and Pintrest are popular choices for sharing content and media. Diigo is a handy tool for sharing useful websites. PebblePad and Thinkspace are both blogging, ePortfolio tools supported by CSU which allow student to publish externally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;apa-ref&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Charles Sturt University. (2014). &lt;a href=&quot;https://policy.csu.edu.au/view.current.php?id=00384&quot;&gt;Social media use policy for staff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Ferris, S. &amp;amp; Wilder, H. (2013) &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csuau.eblib.com.ezproxy.csu.edu.au/patron/FullRecord.aspx?p=1574982&quot;&gt;The plugged in professor: Tips and techniques for teaching with social media&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Ebook Library&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Manca, S. &amp;amp; Ranieri, M. (2016). &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.csu.edu.au/science/article/pii/S0360131516300185&quot;&gt;Facebook and the others. Potentials and obstacles of Social Media for teaching in higher education&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Computers &amp;amp; Education, 95&lt;/em&gt;.  216-230. doi:10.1016/j.compedu.2016.01.012&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;NMC Horizon Report: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nmc.org/pdf/2014-nmc-horizon-report-he-EN.pdf&quot;&gt;2014 Higher Education Edition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.socialmedianews.com.au/social-media-statistics-australia-february-2015/&quot;&gt;Social Media News Australia&lt;/a&gt; 2016. Accessed July 20, 2016 website&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Tomayess, I. (2015). &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csuau.eblib.com.ezproxy.csu.edu.au/patron/Read.aspx?p=4178203&amp;amp;pg=25&quot;&gt;Social Networking in Australia: Opportunities and risks&lt;/a&gt;, In I. Tomayess,  P. Isaias, &amp;amp; P. Kommers, &lt;em&gt;Social networking and education: Global perspectives&lt;/em&gt;. Ebook Library&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;/csulx/js/swiper.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
    var swiper = new Swiper('.swiper-container', {
        nextButton: '.swiper-button-next',
        prevButton: '.swiper-button-prev',
        pagination: '.swiper-pagination',
        paginationClickable: true
    });

&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 14:34:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/csulx/strategy/social-media-streams.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/csulx/strategy/social-media-streams.html</guid>
        
        <category>Learning Communities</category>
        
        <category>Interaction Between Students</category>
        
        <category>Interaction with the Professions</category>
        
        
        <category>strategy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating a Shared Resource</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Critical to establishing a sense of community, is the feeling that group members matter and that one’s needs are satisfied through the collective effort of the group (Yuan and Kim, 2014).  One way to foster such attitudes among students is to ensure they share responsibilities as well as common goals within their study.  Asking students to create shared resources assists the entire cohort to learn together by focussing on a shared goal. One commonly used approach is the  ‘jigsaw’. With this approach students research a particular sub-topic for the benefit of the entire cohort. By sharing their findings with the others, the ‘puzzle’ is completed.  Shared responsibilities and goals build the sense of community and through the process students demonstrate communication skills and utilise the online environment to develop their digital literacies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;engagement&quot;&gt;Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developing engagement within a community requires a focal point, a common goal or aim and the creation of a shared resource does this. The shared nature of the resource creates a goal that students must work towards and provides a measure of accountability.  This equates to incentives as well as rewards through peer recognition. As noted by Wenger, McDermott and Snyder (2002) good community design requires an understanding of the community’s potential to develop and steward knowledge. Shared resources provide a way to test and develop a community in a variety of ways. It collects the learning and reduces the risk of a single point of failure. Students learn and develop important skills like negotiation and communication, which requires a much deeper level of engagement between students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-practice&quot;&gt;In Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;subject&quot;&gt;Subject&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MBA501: Management, People and Organisations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;teaching-staff&quot;&gt;Teaching staff&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wendy Webber&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a post-graduate subject with many students new to CSU, this learning design incorporated digital literacies and professional communication skills while building a sense of community. Each student group examined a contemporary management issue, shared their findings and considered the information presented by their peers. In the end this activity provided the cohort with a collection of presentations which unpacked topics introduced in weekly readings and tutorials&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;implementation&quot;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students were randomly placed into groups, communication tools for student-to-student interaction included the discussion board and folders for sharing artefacts. Each small group of students presented their findings through online meeting sessions. The entire cohort was invited to vote for the ‘best’ presentations via Suveymonkey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guide&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The creation of shared resources requires quite a bit of planning. Lecturers may consider the development of resources in a number of ways. Questions to ponder include: What tools do students need to build resources? How will students communicate and collaborate within their small groups? ‘When completed what will the collection of resources provide the entire cohort? Are they opportunities to share with other cohorts of students?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some key points to consider:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clearly Identify topics to be divided amongst the students&lt;/strong&gt;.  As with any learning activity, it is important to make expectations clear. Let students know what they will be focussing on and what the completed body of knowledge will represent - what will the completed ‘jigsaw’ provide? How much research or other work is expected from each student and how will it be shared? This could be done through discussion board forums, wikis and/or shared folders (ie. resources folder)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allocate student groups to each topic&lt;/strong&gt;. At this point there are some options to consider: is it appropriate for students to self-select or will they be assigned to particular groups&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitor progress&lt;/strong&gt;. Simply keep students on track as you would normally with regular online meeting sessions and announcements.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Share the final product&lt;/strong&gt;. Once all the students or groups have completed their research and prepared their findings, share the larger body of knowledge, which is the completed ‘jigsaw’. This could be done in a variety of ways depending on the initial briefing. For example: if each student wrote a short report they could be combined into a larger book, or a series of Powerpoint slides may be compiled into a slideshow or animation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Debrief&lt;/strong&gt;. After students have had time to consider the efforts of their peers discuss overall findings and what they have learned from their own work and that of others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blackboard Wikis, Blogs and the use of a common space such as a ‘resources’ folder to upload artefacts are all useful tools to develop a shared resources. External technologies like Google Docs or Google Slides can be particularly useful for collaborative authoring and contribution in a way that also provides version tracking and control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;apa-ref&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Palloff, R. &amp;amp; Pratt, K. (2010). &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csuau.eblib.com.ezproxy.csu.edu.au/patron/FullRecord.aspx?p=529967&quot;&gt;Collaborating online: Learning together in community&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Retrieved from EBook Library&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Pozzi, F. (2010). &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com.ezproxy.csu.edu.au/science/article/pii/S0360131509003388&quot;&gt;Using jigsaw and case study for supporting online collaborative learning&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Computer &amp;amp; Education 55&lt;/em&gt;(1), 67-75.
doi: 10.1016/j.compedu.2009.12.003&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Yuan, J. &amp;amp; Kim, C. (2014). &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com.ezproxy.csu.edu.au/doi/10.1111/jcal.12042/full&quot;&gt;Guidelines for facilitating the development of learning communities in online courses&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Computer Assisted Learning, 30&lt;/em&gt;. 220-232. doi: 10.1111/jcal.12042&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wenger, E. &amp;amp; McDermott, R. &amp;amp; Snyder, W.M. (2002). Seven principles for cultivating communities of practice. In &lt;em&gt;Cultivating communities of practice: A guide to managing knowledge&lt;/em&gt;. (pp.49-64). Boston : Harvard Business School Press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 13:55:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/csulx/strategy/creating-shared-resource.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/csulx/strategy/creating-shared-resource.html</guid>
        
        <category>Learning Communities</category>
        
        <category>Interaction Between Students</category>
        
        
        <category>strategy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Orientation to the Environment</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The online learning environment can often be a daunting place for new and continuing students. It lacks the familiarity of a classroom, so it is important that students become familiar with the conventions of the learning management system and how it will be utilised in the teaching of your subject. Clearly defining places and spaces for students to have discussions, making them aware of where information is located, how it’s expected to be accessed and what channels of communication are available are important steps in this process. Ensuring students are comfortable with the environment and the expectations of how they will be learning are key for students navigating their way through their studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;engagement&quot;&gt;Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If students are familiar with the learning environment they will feel more comfortable to engaging in the learning process. If students are unsure of processes or expectations, where to locate information, or how to communicate the learning environment will feel foreign and difficult to work in. Adopting an orientation process in the subject provides the kind of wayfaring and signage that we find in a physical space. Signposting key information and providing logical navigation assist students in finding their way in the online environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-practice&quot;&gt;In Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;subject&quot;&gt;Subject&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SSS032: Introduction to Learning Online&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;teaching-staff&quot;&gt;Teaching staff&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stewart McKinney&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subject &lt;em&gt;SSS032 Introduction to Learning Online&lt;/em&gt; was developed explicitly to orient students to studying online at CSU. Ensuring students are comfortable in using the communication technologies is paramount to their success as it forms the bedrock of their interaction with the peers and teaching staff. Students must be capable of using a variety of i2 and other CSU supported technologies to succeed in their study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;implementation&quot;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subject is open to all students throughout the year and provides them with a scaffolded way of exploring the main tools and features of Interact2. Students are introduced to key technologies through simple videos, and text modules that are then enacted upon through a structured activity. In this way students are provided with a model of how a tool works, and then a practical engagement with it by completing a task. By the end of the course which is around 10 hours in total, students have learnt about Interact2 but have used the tools too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../images/practices/Orientation-to-the-Environment-SSS032.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SSS032 Screenshot&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guide&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Interact2 provides a common interface and set of tools for students, they can be used in quite different ways in the teaching of a subject. Providing students with a “guided tour” of the learning environment is an excellent way to orient them to the space and how the subject will be taught. Simply explaining how and why the different tools will be us ed is a great way to kick off the teaching session and will help in establishing expectations and get keen students off on the right foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could be part of a &lt;a href=&quot;http:///csulx/strategy/welcome-videos.html&quot;&gt;Welcome Video&lt;/a&gt; and displayed prominently on the subject landing page. Labelling the navigation in a consistent and obvious way can provide students with the necessary signposts needed to find relevant and timely information. Some like to utilise the sites landing page to offer students an updated weekly schedule with links to the relevant lessons and resources. A more interactive way of getting students to orient themselves would be to set up an orientation activity. This could be a scavenger hunt where students find hidden items or a quick quiz that tests if students have read important information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video Recordings: A desktop capture in CSU Replay or recording of an Online Meeting session or Screencast-o-matic can be used to ‘show and tell’ your i2 site to students and is very useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subject &lt;em&gt;SSS032 Introduction to Learning Online&lt;/em&gt; is a useful resource for students in itself as it introduces Interact2 tools and a range of online teaching and learning strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 15:20:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/csulx/strategy/orientation-to-the-environment.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/csulx/strategy/orientation-to-the-environment.html</guid>
        
        <category>Learning Communities</category>
        
        <category>Teacher Presence</category>
        
        
        <category>strategy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Guest Lectures</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inviting practitioners and experts to give guest lectures as part of the subject design is an excellent way to provide students with access to the professions. Guest lectures are a way for students to hear and interact with their “peers” in the profession. Experienced practitioners can provide students with an insight into the reality of their work and creates an opportunity to share with students the kinds of tacit skills and knowledge they will need in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;engagement&quot;&gt;Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding guest lectures to your subject is an excellent way for students to engage directly with the professions and gain an insight into contemporary practices. They provide an opportunity for students to not just listen to a presentation but to ask questions and open a dialogue. They provide a simple way of providing students with their first engagement with the profession. Guest lectures also provide a way of forming a greater connections and partnership with the professions as it builds a bridge between the classroom and the workforce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guide&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting started with guest lectures requires a recruitment process to find willing professionals to engage with your students. Professional bodies, both formal and informal, can provide a ready-made network to engage with and seek out speakers. Local small businesses, schools and community groups are another source of potential guests and can provide a different perspective than students may be used to. Planning these lectures to make the most effective use of them content and time requires planning. Aligning the speaker to a specific topic or area of study that students have issues with may assist students making the links required to understand. It may useful to carve out time for question and answers rather than making the session purely one-way. A variation on the lecture is to conduct an interview with the guest and ask students to propose questions as part of a linked activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Meeting&lt;/strong&gt; - Adobe Connect provides an online tool that is perfect for Guest Lectures. Presenters can share slides and documents, share their webcam, interact with student directly or via text chat. It also allows you to record sessions so that students who can’t make it, or who may want to review the presentation can access it later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video Conferencing&lt;/strong&gt; - the new CSU Video Conferencing system makes it easier than ever to engage with the outside world. Guests can log in using just their web browser. It lacks the interactive and recording features of Adobe Connect but may suit some situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skype and Google Hangouts are other options but dealing with large groups of students can be difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;apa-ref&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Algie, J. &amp;amp; Rowland, J. K. (2007). &lt;a href=&quot;http://ro.uow.edu.au/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2162&amp;amp;context=commpapers&quot;&gt;A guest lecturing program to improve students’ applied learning&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Australian and New Zealand Marketing Academy Conference&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 1-6). Dunedin, New Zealand: Australian and New Zealand Marketing Academy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 14:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/csulx/strategy/guest-lectures.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/csulx/strategy/guest-lectures.html</guid>
        
        <category>Interaction with the Professions</category>
        
        
        <category>strategy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Choice Within Assessments</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choice Within Assessments&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Providing greater choice within an assessment is a great way to personalise the learning experience for each individual student. Subject enrolments often include students from a wide range of disciplines and assessment tasks can be developed to cater for this diversity. Questions can be aligned with different discipline areas and ask students to draw on those unique aspects of their society. Student could also have choice around the type of artefact they may produce - from essay through a presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;engagement&quot;&gt;Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allowing students from a range of contexts to apply their own discipline knowledge and draw on their own experiences in their assessment makes the task more relatable and authentic. The student cohort for online learning courses at CSU is quite diverse in terms of the age, location and experience, and this can be a significant asset to a group of learners. Providing students with a choice between multiple questions, pathways and artefacts allows that diversity to be draw out and students can learn from each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guide&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of ways to provide greater choice to students in their assessment tasks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A common question may be responded to with a specific focus on a student’s context and draw from their personal experience or discipline area.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The form of the assessment may reflect the discipline of the student and the forms of communication common to that profession. So a ‘writing task’ may be presented as an essay, a report or news article depending on the student’s course of study.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Students may wish a choice of medium for the assignment. Rather than write a traditional essay student could present their work as a presentation, multimedia artefact or video. This can broaden the student’s range of communication skills and promote a variety of digital literacies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Word, Powerpoint, YouTube,&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 10:03:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/csulx/strategy/choice-within-assessments.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/csulx/strategy/choice-within-assessments.html</guid>
        
        <category>Interaction Between Students</category>
        
        <category>Interaction with the Professions</category>
        
        <category>Flexible &amp; Adaptive Learning</category>
        
        
        <category>strategy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Adapting Learning Resources</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data analytics like those provided by Interact2 Site Analytics, can be used to easily discover student use and engagement patterns for content areas and key learning resources. This data can be used towards making adjustments to learning resources and support during a current session, and informing learning resource and support provision in subsequent subject offerings to allow learner pathways that are more responsive to concept learning difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;engagement&quot;&gt;Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These adaptations demonstrate a responsive approach to teaching in order to meet student needs and address issues related to their engagement with the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-practice&quot;&gt;In Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;subject&quot;&gt;Subject&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PSC102: Botany&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;teaching-staff&quot;&gt;Teaching staff&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Harper &amp;amp; Geoff Burrows&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PSC102 Botany&lt;/em&gt; is a common subject in a number of Bachelor of Agriculture courses and provides a range of resources that if fully utilised will help students succeed in the subject. Information and insights on how students actually use the learning resources provided, and what resources students found to be useful is of immense value towards the development of a more personalised learning approach in a core subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;implementation&quot;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data analytics has provided helpful insights into how students can be helped to succeed in the subject. Providing more personalised learning content, resources and support, allows for a responsive teaching practice and appropriately targeted academic interventions that focus on known problem areas of subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guide&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data analytics are available in a number of systems used at CSU like Interact2 Site Analytics and CSU Replay. This data can be augmented with information from students gathered from the Discussion Forums or later in the Student Evaluation System. Combining these sources can provide useful and informative data from which to analyse student use of learning resources in order to make adjustments. They provide a picture of how many students accessed the resources, and combined with information from students as to what areas they struggled with, teachers can adapt the resources available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be achieved in a variety of different ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Augment existing resources with additional material by injecting additional sources of information.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using existing rich media resources, like YouTube videos, to add explain topic areas. Video and visual resources can often help explain and illustrate difficult concept in different ways.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Link to other sources that describe the topic in different ways to create &lt;a href=&quot;https://hapgood.us/2016/05/13/choral-explanations/&quot;&gt;Choral Explanations&lt;/a&gt; so that students can find an explanation that relates to their way of thinking.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Present students with options and different ways to access learning materials. Some students may prefer to read, some on screen and some on paper, others may prefer to listen or watch their resources. Data analysis can help identify student preferences.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create supplementary resources yourself, like videos, that react and respond to student queries, questions and misunderstandings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interact2 Site Analytics, Tests and Surveys, Discussion Forums, YouTube, Smart Sparrow,&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 10:03:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/csulx/strategy/adapting-learning-resources.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/csulx/strategy/adapting-learning-resources.html</guid>
        
        <category>Flexible &amp; Adaptive Learning</category>
        
        <category>Interactive Resources</category>
        
        
        <category>strategy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Video Lectures</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video Lectures&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;element-tags&quot;&gt;Element Tags&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teacher Presence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recording Video Lectures for online students provides a richer engagement with the subject concepts than is possible with text. The sound and ‘live’ nature of the resource helps to convey the presence of the teacher. The tone of voice and other aspects of the audio contribute to students understanding of the topic and possible nuances in concepts. Video provides a rich medium to convey information as it can combine visual elements with animation and footage of the lecturer speaking. It also provides an avenue to embed and share some of the teacher’s personality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;engagement&quot;&gt;Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video Lectures provide a version of ‘the lecture’ that is more tailored to the online environment. CSU Replay recordings of the internal lecture can sometimes have issues with the audio as the lecturer moves in relation to the microphone and can come across to students as second best. Specifically recording videos shifts the priority to the online students and opens up new possibilities for internal students as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-practice&quot;&gt;In Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;subject&quot;&gt;Subject&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SCI103: Communicating Environmental Data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;teaching-staff&quot;&gt;Teaching staff&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ana Horta&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Video Lectures help the online students to feel that they are not missing out because of their study mode. They provide an effective way of augmenting the existing content students have and provide a timely way to address questions and provide support to the whole cohort of students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;implementation&quot;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SCI103 video lectures include screen-captures as well as audio and video, and mostly range from 20-40 minutes. They were created to provide online students with more coverage and explanation of the concepts presented in the online modules, textbook and recommended readings. Like lectures, there is one for each week. Through these video lectures the voice and personality of the lecturer comes through as a real human being, and so helps convey teacher presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;swiper-container&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;swiper-wrapper image-container&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;swiper-slide&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/practices/video-lectures-SCI103-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;video screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;swiper-slide&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/practices/video-lectures-SCI103-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;video screenshot&quot; /&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;swiper-slide&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/practices/video-lectures-SCI103-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;vide screenshot&quot; /&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;swiper-pagination&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;swiper-button-next&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;swiper-button-prev&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guide&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video lectures can be utilised in a variety of ways to augment and support your teaching and engagement with students. They provide a way to communicate directly with the class as a whole but also provide a channel to embed your personality into the subject too. There are however some pitfalls in that make transferring lectures done face-to-face quite challenging, but also some important affordance you can take advantage of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maintaining Attention&lt;/strong&gt; - This can be a challenge in a video and it’s why many experts suggest keeping the length of online videos short. There are often more distractions available when studying online and it’s a lot easier to duck off to another Tab in the browser than it is to leave a classroom.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audio and Visuals&lt;/strong&gt; - Videos require an effort to both audio and visual components. Talking to a single slide is quite common in a face-to-face lecture because there is other visual stimuli available, but that’s not the case in a video. Spending less time on a slide and creating some visual diversity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pause and Rewind&lt;/strong&gt; - One of the unique aspects of video lectures is that it provides students with the ability to pause and rewind. Pausing means that they can come back to the lecture and provides students with added flexibility. The rewind allows students to re-watch the video multiple times. This is great for demonstrations or showing processes to student. It allows them to see how it fits together.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communicate&lt;/strong&gt; - Use video lectures to maintain a dialogue with your students. Keep them up to date with their progress, upcoming deadlines, tips for study and assessment tasks and respond to their questions from the forums or email as a group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.csu.edu.au/division/dit/staff/training/self-help/teaching-technology-and-support&quot;&gt;CSU Replay&lt;/a&gt; provides a desktop capture solution that allows you to record and upload presentations back into the system for students to access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;apa-ref&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Anderson, T., Rourke, L., Garrison, D. R., &amp;amp; Archer, W. (2001). Assessing teacher presence in a computer conferencing context. &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://auspace.athabascau.ca/bitstream/2149/2725/2141/assessing_teaching_presence.pdf%20on%20Oct-2014&quot;&gt;Journal of the Asynchronous Learning Network, 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;(2),&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Anderson T. (Ed.), (2008) &lt;em&gt;Theory and practice of online learning&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 343-365). Athabasca University, Edmonton, AB: AU Press.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Arbaugh, J. B. (2001). How Instructor Immediacy Behaviors Affect Student Satisfaction and Learning in Web-Based Courses. [Article]. &lt;em&gt;Business Communication Quarterly, 64&lt;/em&gt;(4), 42-54.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Borup, J. West, R.E., Graham C.R. (2012) &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S109675161100073X&quot;&gt;The Internet and Higher Education&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, Elsevier&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Dunlap, J. C., &amp;amp; Lowenthal, P. R. (2009). Tweeting the Night Away: Using Twitter to Enhance Social Presence. [Article]. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Information Systems Education, 20&lt;/em&gt;(2), 129-135.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Garrison, D. R., &amp;amp; Arbaugh, J. B. (2007). Researching the community of inquiry framework: Review, issues, and future directions. &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.iheduc.2007.04.001&quot;&gt;The Internet and Higher Education, 10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;(3), 157-172. and p.168&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Ostashewski, N. (2015). A tale of three MOOCs: Designing for meaningful teacher presence in large-enrolment courses. In S. Carliner, C. Fulford &amp;amp; N. Ostashewski (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of EdMedia: World Conference on Educational Media and Technology 2015&lt;/em&gt; (Vol. 2015, pp. 1279-1284): Association for the Advancement of Computing in Education (AACE).&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Sheridan, T. B. (1992). Musings on telepresence and virtual presence. &lt;em&gt;Presence: Teleoper. Virtual Environ.&lt;/em&gt;, 1(1), 120-126 mentions video as part of conveying telepresence&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Swan, K., Shea, P., Richardson, J., Ice, P., Garrison, D., Cleveland-Innes, M., et al. (2008). Validating a measurement tool of presence in online communities of inquiry. &lt;em&gt;E-mentor, 2&lt;/em&gt;(24), 1-12.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;/csulx/js/swiper.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
    var swiper = new Swiper('.swiper-container', {
        nextButton: '.swiper-button-next',
        prevButton: '.swiper-button-prev',
        pagination: '.swiper-pagination',
        paginationClickable: true
    });

&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 16:20:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/csulx/strategy/video-lectures.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/csulx/strategy/video-lectures.html</guid>
        
        <category>Teacher Presence</category>
        
        <category>Interactive Resources</category>
        
        
        <category>strategy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating Rich Media Artefacts</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The creation of rich media artefacts including photographic evidence, video records and multimedia presentations by learners can provide an authentic way for learners to develop a variety of digital literacies, technical and communication skills that will be useful in the professions. In addition, the co-construction of rich media artefacts can also offer an authentic collaborative experience for learners and due to advancing and readily available mobile technologies, a range of interactive experiences can be integrated into the collaborative learning environment. In many ways rich media such as video can provide better evidence of students,  their skills and abilities than written assignments which can greatly improve the effectiveness of the assessment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;engagement&quot;&gt;Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of rich media artefacts can create an engaging learning experience by shifting the attention away from the physical product and on to the learning process. Learners can also engage further with self and peer assessment and reflection in an authentic setting. Working with rich media provides an alternative to written assessment tasks and a way for students to express themselves in different ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guide&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rich Media provides a different way for students to document, explain or demonstrate their learning. It provides ways of capturing information about what students are learning that are not possible in other mediums. Rich media can capture important information about the student’s environment and situation and provides a way to capture more authentic tasks - in particular getting students to demonstrate and reflect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some important considerations for structuring assessments that utilise rich media include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build additional work around the task. Developing rich media can be time consuming so don’t use it as an add on, but look at opportunities to centre other assessments or activities the student’s work to make it worthwhile.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use it for self-evaluation and diagnosis. Ask students to record themselves and let them review their performance and get them to link their work to theory and the profession.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build relevant skills with a focus on the what they would benefit from in the profession. What would they do on the job? Tasks that are common and adaptable are presentations of information and literature, in depth discussion of a situation or topic, or taking a side and creating an argument for a debate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rich media lends itself particularly well to engaging in peer-to-peer evaluation and feedback on the work. Students could be asked not just to to identify issues but to make suggestion and provide constructive feedback which is often quite challenging, but engages a deeper level of knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To know if using rich media is the right choice in your subject then ask yourself some of the following questions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can it provide you with better evidence to assess your students?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Will it capture the student’s learning better than an essay?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is it a more authentic and more contextual way to assess the student?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many readily available tools that students can utilise to produce rich media artefacts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mobile devices can record audio and video as well as take photos.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use Powerpoint and similar software to combine audio and visuals.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;YouTube, Vimeo, SoundCloud and Flickr provide free and easy ways for students to publish their artefacts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;apa-ref&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Klapdor, T. (2014). Recording video on your Mobile, &lt;em&gt;CSU mHub&lt;/em&gt;. Retrieved 19 July 2016, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://mhub.csu.edu.au/guides/recording-video-on-your-mobile/&quot;&gt;http://mhub.csu.edu.au/guides/recording-video-on-your-mobile/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 12:34:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/csulx/strategy/creating-rich-media-artefacts.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/csulx/strategy/creating-rich-media-artefacts.html</guid>
        
        <category>Interactive Resources</category>
        
        <category>E-Assessment</category>
        
        
        <category>strategy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Computer Based Exams</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A computer based exam is an exam which replaces the more traditional paper based exam and may or may not involve the use of a remote indivigulator to monitor the student/s during the completion of the task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;engagement&quot;&gt;Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The provision of computer based exams provide students with a contemporary and flexible method of completing assessment tasks. This approach is more in keeping with the ways that students complete other assessment tasks (i.e. with computers) and is a more flexible practice than the requirement for students to travel to their nearest exam centre to sit a paper based exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-practice&quot;&gt;In Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;subject&quot;&gt;Subject&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HIP 202: Research for Health Practice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;teaching-staff&quot;&gt;Teaching staff&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Kylie Murphy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;HIP202 Research For Health Practice&lt;/em&gt; is a second year common subject undertaken by most students within the school of Community Health at CSU. The aim of this subject is to begin these students on the journey to becoming evidence based health practitioners. This subject is designed to provide students with an introductory experience to utilising information and research and applying this knowledge to the specific problems of their health discipline/s. Throughout this subject students are taught to, and get the chance to implement a range of skills including the development of sophisticated database search terms (including Boolean operators) creating and saving database permalinks, understanding the structure and function of a wide range of qualitative and quantitative research approaches and associated documentation. Students become skilled at doing all of these things to solve authentic problems over the course of the subject, so the apparent misalignment between the subject and it’s main assessment task, a paper based exam, were clear. Providing students with a large collection of printed resources was both in-authentic and wasteful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;implementation&quot;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating a suitable replacement task for this paper based exam revolved around firstly determining alignment between subject outcomes, the assessable components in question and then ensuring that students could access a fair and well designed assessment which was supported by current CSU platforms. In the end, the Interact2 test centre was chosen as the platform because of the support available and (through an extended period of testing and trialing) the ability to remove technical glitches. Over 190 students completed the assessment task simultaneously in a three hour period during exam week in July 2016, with all three student cohorts reporting an increased satisfaction of the subject and the assessment practices, as measured by the student experience survey. Key messages from this implementation process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A team development process is crucial-as the academic, developing and building a vision for what you want to achieve in innovating in your assessments is crucial, but getting people around you so that you can access the right skills at the right time is key-your educational designer can support you with project management on these larger tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sustainability versus ‘do-ability’-at some point, when you have less support, will you be able to carry out some of the trouble shooting yourself? Investing time upfront in understanding how the system will work will gain you time in the long term.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Starting point-critically analyse what you are offering as assessment, not just how you are offering it-consider all parts when undertaking assessment changes-who, what, when, where, how, why…and for who.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be explicit in linking between learning outcomes and design of the e-exam-particularly useful so that students could see why the changes were being made in this research and information literacy subject&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integrate the e-exam into the delivery of the subject i.e. providing advance notice through announcements, practice e-exams, pre-emptive student troubleshooting tips, familiarisation. In essence, consider the user experience of your e-exam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guide&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking to implement a computer based exam within your subject/s, there are some important considerations to make when planning this approach:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integrity - Given that many exams at CSU are relatively high stakes, it is important to take into account the ways which you will maintain the integrity of the assessment task so that students are assessed on a level playing field. If you are planning on utilizing the increasing range of remote invigilator services available (see here) these concerns are somewhat minimized as the student’s identification will be verified by the invigilator.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design - If you are not planning on utilising these kinds invigilator services, the design of the exam can increase the integrity of the assessment. For example, an exam containing extended answer sections to complement multiple choice questions gives you as the assessor greater opportunity to cross reference any work against the student’s prior performance within the subject.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exam platform - It is possible to build an effective e-exam within the interact2 test environment. A growing practice is the creation of one overall exam which consists of several ‘tests’, each of which can only be accessed once the previous one has been reviewed and submitted. This has several advantages including the fact that you can choose to make students complete the exam in a specified or random order, and as a result it minimises chances for integrity breaches. In addition, there are a range of functionalities such as the ability to store audio, video and files within the test environment, these being available from other areas of your subject site. Additionally, utilizing the supported test centre functionalities within interact2 means that you can schedule specific opening and closing times for these assessment tasks, meaning that support can be organised around this timeframe.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Another effective safeguard in ensuring integrity is undertaking a range of pre-moderation activities. In a typical exam environment, students will be presented with the same scenario. In an e-exam, it is possible to present a range of scenarios in which students are asked to apply knowledge and skills. Key to this is the development and pre-moderation of a range of equivalent scenarios that students must respond to. The alternative to this aspect is providing one scenario but a range of ways to respond. Building a range of options makes it harder for collusion to occur, but it is important to follow a rigorous pre- moderation process.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are other non-supported technologies for offering e-exams, but utilising these is problematic as they will not link to CSU systems such as grade centre. In some situations bespoke solutions can be created in order to embed currently unsupported software platforms, but this process requires an extensive planning and implementation time frame.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interact2 - various tools including Test Centre and Grade Centre are important in the design and development of your computer based exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content Creation - you may need to utilise a range of tools including word processing programs such as Word or Pages. Alternatively, Test Centre does have a range of content creation tools including Word/Audio/Video which can be deployed in the test environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 10:37:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/csulx/strategy/computer-based-exams.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/csulx/strategy/computer-based-exams.html</guid>
        
        <category>Flexible &amp; Adaptive Learning</category>
        
        <category>E-Assessment</category>
        
        
        <category>strategy</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
